Jean Sovatkin Picker papers, 1915-1988
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS
  - United Nations Association of the United States of America (UNA-USA) (Box 13)
    - Public Relations
      - Promotion of Eleanor Roosevelt: Her Day, 1973-74 (Box 22, Folder 27)
      - Response to Heritage Foundation, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 28-29)
    - Publications and Educational materials
      - General, 1980-83, undated (Box 22, Folder 3-)
      - "An Assessment of UNA's Accomplishments," 1978-81 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Draft: "The National Program of UNA-USA," 1978 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Portfolio of teaching aids, 1975-78 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - "The United Nations: In Search of Answers" Vista, Sep/Oct 1972 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - "Teaching about the United Nations," Feb 1981 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Fact sheets, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Educational kits
        - Decade for Women, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 7-9)
          [see also oversize]
        - "Operation Turning Point: End the Arms Race," 1977 (Box 23, Folder 10)
        - A Study and Action Pack for World Development, circa 1975 (Box 23, Folder 11)
        - UNAKIT, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 12-13)
        - International Peacekeeping Program, 1971-72 (Box 23, Folder 14-15)
        - Environmental program, 1971-72 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Model UN
        - Guide to Delegate Preparation, 1982-83 (Box 23, Folder 17)
        - Calendar, 1985-86 (Box 23, Folder 18)
        - Workshop at UN for UNESCO associated schools, 14-20 Aug 1977 (Box 23, Folder 19)
        - UN Conference on the Law of the Sea, 1974-75 (Box 23, Folder 20-21)
        - World Population Conference, 19-30 Aug 1974 (Box 23, Folder 22)
        - World Food Conference, 5-16 Nov 1974 (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - Program Planning for UN Day, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - "Time to Lead: Mandate for Action: UN Day Program Manual," 1983 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - "Partnerships in Meeting Basic Needs" with National Education Association, Nov 1981 (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Newsletters: Interdependent, Issues, and Washington Weekly Report, 1980-84 (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - Issues before the General Assembly, 1977-82 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
      - Issues of the 80s fact sheets, 1980-83 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Annual Program Manual, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
      - Manual of Chapter Operations, Apr 1980 (Box 24, Folder 6-11)
      - Editor's Guide to the UN, 1978-79 (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
      - "Toward a World without Hunger," 1980 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - "Shaping the Global Agenda: Priorities for US Policy in International Organizations," 1983 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - "Purposes and Means: A Sensible Guide for Policy on International Organization," 1983 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - "The UN at Thirty" drafts, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Events and conferences
      - General, 1975-81 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - 18th Annual UN Concert and dinner fundraiser, 21 Oct 1978 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - National convention, May 1983 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - NATO trips
        - Notes by Harvey Picker, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 21)
        - Invited people, 1983-85 (Box 24, Folder 22-23)
        - Coordination of annual visits, 1983-85 (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
        - Articles and news clippings, 1981-85 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
      - Miscellaneous meetings
        - Commodity agreements and 7th Special Session, 11 Jun 1975 (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Nonproliferation with Hans Blix, 20 May 1983 (Box 25, Folder 10)
        - Planning group for UN Management and Decision-making Study, 27 Mar 1985 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Affiliated organizations, 1975-82
      - United States Association for the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, 1968-74 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - United States Mission to the United Nations
        - General
          - General, 1969-78 (Box 25, Folder 14)
          - Articles about the UN, 1973-75 (Box 25, Folder 15)
          - Report, "Social Development in the UN," circa 1970-77 (Box 25, Folder 16)
          - Report, "Coordination and Concerted Action in the United Nations System of Organizations," Department of State: Bureau of International Organization Affairs, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 17)
          - Speeches and statements by Jean Picker, 1968-77, undated (Box 25, Folder 18-27)
          - Reports by Jean Picker (Box 26)
            - "Prospects for More Effective UN Actions in the Field of Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice," 6 Jul 1973 (Box 26, Folder 1)
            - "Report on Children," undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
        - General Assembly
          - General
            - General overview, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 3)
            - Officers, 1963-72 (Box 26, Folder 4)
            - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 5)
            - Mission Liaison Officers information notebook, 9 Jun 1971 (Box 26, Folder 6)
            - Notes, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 7-14)
            - Schedules, Sep-Dec 1968 (Box 26, Folder 15)
            - Speeches and statements by Jean Picker, 1968-76 (Box 26, Folder 16-18)
            - Position papers and reports, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 19)
            - News clippings, Sep-Dec 1968 (Box 26, Folder 20)
          - Correspondence
            - Memoranda, 1968-69 (Box 26, Folder 21)
            - Telegrams to/from Secretary of State and US Mission to UN, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 22)
            - Telegrams to/from Secretary of State and US Mission to UN, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
            - Third Committee: correspondence and invitations, Sep-Dec 1968 (Box 27, Folder 3)
          - 23rd Session
            - Annotated programs, agendas, and telegrams, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 4)
            - Capital punishment, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
            - Human Rights in Occupied Territories: Picker statement drafts, 5-6 Dec 1968 (Box 27, Folder 7)
            - International Year for Human Rights
              - General, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 8)
              - Annotated publications (Box 27, Folder 9-11)
              - Publication: "Human Rights," 1968 (Box 27, Folder 12)
              - Memoranda, press release, and draft declaration, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 13)
              - Speeches by Jean Picker, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
              - Notes, Nov-Dec 1968 (Box 27, Folder 16-17)
              - High Commissioner, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 18)
              - Position papers and state department telegrams, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 1)
              - Symposium, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 2)
              - "The Organization of American States and the Protection of Human Rights," 1968 (Box 28, Folder 3)
            - Natural Disasters, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 4)
            - Refugees
              - General, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 5)
              - Election of High Commissioner for Refugees, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 6)
            - War Crimes
              - General, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 7)
              - Notes, 8-15 Oct 1968 (Box 28, Folder 8-9)
              - Statement and drafts by Jean Picker, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 10)
              - Annotated UN publications, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 11)
            - World Social Situation
              - General and statements by Jean Picker, Oct-Nov 1968 (Box 28, Folder 12)
              - Notes, Nov 1968 (Box 28, Folder 13-14)
              - Annotated draft resolutions, Oct-Nov 1968 (Box 28, Folder 15)
            - Youth, 1968-70 (Box 28, Folder 13-19)
          - 24th session
            - Social Development, 1969-71 (Box 28, Folder 20)
          - 25th session
            - Elderly and aged, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 21)
          - 28th session
            - Elderly and aged, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 22-24)
          - 29th session
            - United States positions (annotated), 1974 (Box 29, Folder 1)
          - 30th session
            - General, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 2)
            - Unified Approach to the Analysis of Planning of Development
              - Draft resolutions, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
              - Correspondence regarding Soviet draft resolution, Oct-Nov 1975 (Box 29, Folder 5)
          - 31st session
            - General (including Picker statements), 1976 (Box 29, Folder 6)
            - Finished items, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 7)
            - National Experience in Achieving Far-Reaching Social and Economic Changes, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 8-10)
        - Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC)
          - General, 1969-73 (Box 29, Folder 11)
          - Commission for Social Development (CSD)
            - General
              - General, 1970-77 (Box 29, Folder 12)
              - Margaret Mead's comments on meeting of Panel on Social Development, 1963-64 (Box 29, Folder 13)
              - Report, circa May 1969 (Box 29, Folder 14)
              - Study of CSD, 1969-76 (Box 29, Folder 15)
              - Report on 21st-24th sessions, 1970-75 (Box 29, Folder 16)
              - Speeches and statements by Jean Picker, undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
              - Membership, 1970-73 (Box 29, Folder 18)
              - Notes
                - 1969-73 (Box 29, Folder 19-22)
                - 1973-77 (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
            - Correspondence
              - Memoranda
                - Outgoing, 1969-77, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
                - Incoming, 1968-77 (Box 30, Folder 5)
                - Third party, 1970-77 (Box 30, Folder 6)
              - Telegrams: State Department to US Mission to UN, 1969-73 (Box 30, Folder 7-9)
            - Sessions
              - 19th: annotated report, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 10)
              - 20th
                - General information, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 11)
                - Reports and position papers
                - Position papers, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 12)
                - Speeches and statements by Picker, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 13)
                - Report of U.S. delegation: draft, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 14)
                - Report by Special Rapporteurs on Technical Cooperative Activities in Social Development, 26 Feb 1969 (Box 30, Folder 15-16)
                - Agenda items
                - Second UN Development Decade, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 17)
                - UN Research Institute for Social Development (RISD), 1969 (Box 30, Folder 18-19)
                - Work Programme, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 20-21)
              - 21st
                - Position papers and reports, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 1)
                - "Toward a Set of Social Indicators," 1969-70 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
                - Speeches and statements by Jean Picker, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 4)
                - Social Policy and Planning
                - General, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 5)
                - "Notes on Development of Concept of Social Planning in UN," 15 May 1969 (Box 31, Folder 6)
                - Report of meeting of experts in Social Policy and Planning, Feb 1970 (Box 31, Folder 7)
                - Symposium on Social Policy and Planning, Jun 1970 (Box 31, Folder 8-10)
                - Preparatory committee for Second UN Development Decade, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 11)
              - 22nd
                - Position papers, Mar 1971 (Box 31, Folder 12)
                - Speeches, statements, and reports by Jean Picker, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 13)
                - Report: "Social Development in Eastern European Socialist Countries and the Soviet Union," 1971 (Box 31, Folder 14)
                - Program proposals, 1970-71 (Box 31, Folder 15)
                - Notes by Secretary General (annotated), 1971 (Box 31, Folder 16)
                - Notes and comments, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 17)
                - Agenda items
                - Criminality and Social Change, 1970-71 (Box 31, Folder 18-19)
                - Social Security, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 20-21)
                - World Social Situation, 1970-71 (Box 31, Folder 22)
              - World Social Situation, 1970-71 (Box 32, Folder 1)
                - World Wide Programme of Research and Training in Regional Development, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 2)
            - 23rd
              - General, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 3)
              - Position papers, statements, and reports
                - Position papers, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
                - Speeches, statements and reports by Jean Picker, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 6)
                - Crime control report, 6 Jul 1973 (Box 32, Folder 7)
                - Annotated report on Unified Approach, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 8)
                - Annotated report on 23rd Session, Feb-Mar 1973 (Box 32, Folder 9)
            - 24th
              - General
                - Agenda and list of representatives, 1974-75 (Box 32, Folder 10)
                - Notes on participants and commission members, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 11)
                - Provisional summary record of 602nd meeting, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 12)
                - Corrections to provisional summary records, Jan-Feb 1975 (Box 32, Folder 13)
                - Proposed US withdrawal from CSD, Mar 1975 (Box 32, Folder 14-15)
                - Position papers, 1974-75 (Box 32, Folder 16)
                - Correspondence and invitations, 1974-75 (Box 32, Folder 17)
                - Department of State telegrams, 2 Dec 1974-30 Jan 1975 (Box 32, Folder 18)
                - Report to U. S. Secretary of State, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 19)
                - Draft resolutions, Jan 1975 (Box 32, Folder 20)
                - Statements on work program by Jean Picker, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 21)
                - Agenda items
                - Item 3: World Social Situation
                - General, 1974-75 (Box 32, Folder 22)
                - Speech and statements by Jean Picker, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 23)
                - Annotated report, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 24)
                - Mid-Term Review and Appraisal, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 25)
                - Item 4: Social indicators, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 26-28)
                - Item 6: Unified Approach, 1973-75 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
                - Item 7: Crime control and prevention, 1973-75 (Box 33, Folder 3)
                - Item 8: Popular participation, 1974-75 (Box 33, Folder 4)
                - Item 9: Statement on Youth and draft resolution by Jean Picker, 8 Jan 1975 (Box 33, Folder 5)
                - Item 10: Rehabilitation of the disabled, Aug 1974-75 (Box 33, Folder 6)
                - Item 11: Programme objectives for Medium Term Plan, 1976-79, 1974-75 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
                - Item 12: Research Institute for Social Development (RISD), 1974-75 (Box 33, Folder 9)
                - Item 13: Migrant workers, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 10)
                - Item 15: Consideration of provisional agenda, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 11)
                - Item 16: Adoption of report of CSD to ECOSOC, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 12)
                - Notes, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 13)
            - 25th
              - General
                - Agenda, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 14)
                - Membership, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 15)
                - Position papers, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 16-17)
              - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 18)
              - Statements and reports
                - Statements by Jean Picker, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 19)
                - Statements by others, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 20)
                - Draft resolutions, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 21)
                - US Report on 25th Session, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 22)
              - Agenda items
                - Item 3: World Social Situation, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 23)
                - Item 4: Review and Appraisal of the International Social Development (Box 33)
                - General, 1969-77 (Box 33, Folder 24)
                - Annotated reports, 1976-77 (Box 33, Folder 25-27)
                - Statements by others, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 1)
                - Item 6: distribution of national income, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 2)
                - Item 7: outflow of trained personnel from developing to developed countries, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 3)
                - Item 8: crime prevention and control, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 4)
                - Item 9: aged and social security, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 5)
                - Item 10: youth policies, 1976-77 (Box 34, Folder 6-7)
                - Item 12: Unified Approach, 1976-77 (Box 34, Folder 8)
                - Item 14: Program objectives for the medium term plan (1978-81) and progress report 1975-76 (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
              - Notes, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 11-13)
        - Committee on Review and Appraisal, 1972-73 (Box 34, Folder 14-20)
        - Social Committee
          - General, 1971-75 (Box 34, Folder 21)
          - Statements by Jean Picker, 1972-75 (Box 34, Folder 22)
          - Notes, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 23)
        - Social Indicators, 1972-74 (Box 34, Folder 24-25)
        - Sessions
          - 46th: Position papers, notes, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 26)
          - 56th: National experience in achieving far-reaching social and economic changes for the purpose of social progress, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 1)
          - 58th: position papers, news clippings, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 2)
        - Working Group on Rationalization, circa 1973-74 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Events
        - Conference on Organization and Procedures of the UN, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 4)
        - Congress on the Prevention of Crime and Treatment of Offenders, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 5)
        - Conference on the Human Environment, 1971-84 (Box 35, Folder 6-8)
        - Conference on Trade and Development, May 1986 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - World Youth Assembly, 1969-73 (Box 35, Folder 10-11)
      - Miscellaneous committees
        - Host Country Advisory Committee
          - General, 1970-73 (Box 35, Folder 12)
          - Draft: summary overview, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 13)
        - United Nations Centre for Development, Planning, Projections, and Policy, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 14)
        - United Nations Centre for Social Development and Humanitarian Affairs: Commission on the Status of Women, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 15)
        - United Nations Department for Disarmament Affairs, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 16)
        - United Nations Development Program: Jackson Capacity Study, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 17)
        - United Nations Division for Economic and Social Information, Apr 1986 (Box 35, Folder 18)
        - United Nations Division for Palestinian Rights, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 19)
        - United Nations Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East, 1970-72 (Box 35, Folder 20)
        - United Nations Economic Committee: International Women's Year Conference, 1973-75 (Box 35, Folder 21)
        - The United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 22)
        - United Nations Fund for Population Activities, May 1986 (Box 35, Folder 23)
        - United Nations Special Committee on Principles of International Law, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - United States National Commission for UNESCO
      - General, 1973-74 (Box 35, Folder 25)
      - Human Rights Task Force, 1972-76 (Box 35, Folder 26-27)
      - UN Decade for Action to Combat Racism, 1973-74 (Box 35, Folder 28-30)
      - Women's World Banking, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 31-32)
- SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES
  - Adoption, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Crime, 1950-73 (Box 36, Folder 2-3)
  - Foreign Aid, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Healthcare, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 5-6)
  - Housing, circa 1968 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Land Reform, 1970-71 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Latin America, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Mentally Retarded, circa 1968-69 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Nigeria: Biafran conflict, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Rehabilitation, 1964-69 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Social Planning, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Social Welfare, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Volunteers, 1969-85 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Women, 1961-73 (Box 36, Folder 16-19)
  - World Bank, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Youth, 1967-76 (Box 36, Folder 21-24)
- MEMORABILIA
  - UN Youth for Peace paperweight, 1970 (Box 37)
  - UN Decade for Women pin, 1976-1986 (Box 37)
  - UN Commemorative stamps, circa 1970s (Box 37)
  - Hair Comb enclosed, 31 Oct 1968 Nandini Beharry to Jean Picker (Box 37)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - SERIES I. BIOGRAHICAL MATERIALS AND PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Invitation to White House Conference on International Cooperation, Nov-Dec 1965 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Photograph, 50th Birthday of Edward J. Sovatkin, 7 Feb 1936 (Box 37)
    - "China Trip" poster for photograph exhibition at Smith College Museum of Art, 16 Sep-24 Oct 1976 (Box 37)
    - "The Pickers in Peking," Marian Blanchard, The Colgate Scene, circa 1976 (Box 37)
  - SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS
    - Committee of Correspondence: pamphlet, n.d.; "Reds' Photographs on Germ Warfare Exposed as Fakes," New York Times, 3 Apr 1952 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Foreign Policy Association: financial report, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Institute for World Order: financial report, 1974 (Box 37)
    - United Nations Association of the USA
      - Audits and budgets, 1972-87, undated (Box 37, Folder 4-5)
      - "1971 Tanker Traffic and Oil Flow," map, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - "Study and Action Pack for World Development," posters and postcard set, 1974 (Box 37)
      - World Population Year fact sheet, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - International Women's Year poster, 1975 (Box 37)
      - "Financing the UN System: Comparative Contributions of Member States," 1976 poster (Box 37)
      - "The United Nations and the Law of the Sea," fact sheet, 1976 (Box 37)
      - The Diplomatic World Bulletin, 19 Oct 1981 (Box 37)
      - Reprint of op-eds on Reaganomics, Fund for Peace, Mar 1982 (Box 37)
      - "Surface Distribution of Ferromanganese Deposits on the Ocean Floor," map, undated (Box 37)
      - United Nations Day poster, undated (Box 37)
    - United States Mission to the United Nations: "Nazi Crimes in Poland, 1939-45" map and booklet, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - "The United Nations and What You Should Know about It," by Jean Picker and Eleanor Roosevelt: galley, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Chinese newspaper from Jean Picker's trip, 1975 (Map-case drawer 56)
    - "Study and Action Pack for World Development," circa 1974 (Map-case drawer 56)
    - Poster, UN General Assembly, Second Special Session on Disarmament, 1982 (Map-case drawer 56)
    - United Nations Development Programme poster, undated (Map-case drawer 56)
    - Tables, Law of the Sea, undated (Map-case drawer 56)